Guide to the Alumni Class materials, 1823-1998 MS2130
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Diplomas, certificates, awards, 1826-1995; MS2130 Series 5; 3 Linear feet (Flat box 13, Flat box 37, Box 35, Flat box 38, Folder 1, Box 10, Box 4, Box 5, Box 11, Flat box 28, Box 31)
  - Pyramid Award, Pyramid Pin, GWU medallion, and Letterman certificate, 1925 ca. (Box 31, Folder 8)
    Francis Brown earned A.B (1924), LL.B. (1926), and LL.M. (1927) degrees from George Washington University. He later worked as the Attorney Examiner, Bureau of Air Mail, Interstate Commerce Commission. This material includes a Pyramid Award, Pyramid Pin, GWU medallion, and Letterman certificate. Mr. Brown donated the materials to University Archives in 1991. Formerly ACC#164.
  - Muriel Parry awards, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
    Glass paperweight from alumna Muriel Hope Parry. It is inscribed, "GW/ Centuries Campaign/ The George Washington University". It was donated to the University Archives by Hilda Jay in January 2006.
  - Muriel Parry award, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
    Award given to alumna Muriel Hope Parry. It is a glass square block (4"x 4") with a silver metal incased in it. The front of the metal reads, "For Honorable Service/ Muriel Hope Parry, 1947-1973". The back of the metal has the Central Intelligence Agency insignia on it. The rim of the metal notes that it is .999+ pure silver. It was donated to the University Archives by Hilda Jay in January 2006.
  - Muriel Parry award, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
    Award given to alumna Muriel Hope Parry. This rectangular glass (6"x 4") sits on a wooden block and has a metal affixed to the front of the glass. The metal reads, "The Luther Rice Society, 1821". The glass is inscribed, "The George Washington University / Henry Clay Associates". The It was donated to the University Archives by Hilda Jay in January 2006.
  - Muriel Parry award, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
    Award given to alumna Muriel Hope Parry. This square wooden block has a mini George Washington metal statuette affixed to the top. An inscription on the wooden block reads, "The George Washington Society, Muriel Parry". It was donated to the University Archives by Hilda Jay in January 2006.
  - Diploma of Francis Henry Strayer, 06/05/1935 (Flat box 37, Folder 1)
    B.S. in Physical Education; formerly Acc#507
  - Diploma of Francis Henry Strayer, 06/14/1939 (Flat box 37, Folder 2)
    Master of Arts; formerly Acc#507
  - Athletic letter of Francis Henry Strayer, 1935 ca. (Flat box 37, Folder 3)
    Athletic letter: buff "W" with blue "G" in the middle; formerly Acc#507
  - Silver tray inscribed HSH, 1890 (Box 44)
    Silver tray inscribed HSH, and "presented by Columbian College of 1890."
- Cherry Tree yearbooks, 1933-1941; MS2130 Series 6; 0.5 Linear feet (Box 18)
  This series consists of Cherry Tree yearbooks that were donated by Alumni. They range in date from 1933 to 1941.
  - Francis Henry Strayer's 1933 Cherry Tree yearbook (Box 6, Folder 8)
    This 1933 George Washington University yearbook was donated by alumnus Francis Henry Strayer. In these yearbooks are included personal notations by Strayer concerning fellow classmates. Formerly Acc 203.
  - Francis Henry Strayer's 1935 Cherry Tree yearbook (Box 6, Folder 9)
    This 1935 George Washington University yearbook was donated by alumnus Francis Henry Strayer. In these yearbooks are included personal notations by Strayer concerning fellow classmates. Formerly Acc 203.
  - 1938 Cherry Tree Yearbook (Box 18, Folder 1)
    This is the 1938 Cherry Tree yearbook of Grant Sherk, Jr. An inspription on the inside cover reads, "Grant R. Sherk, Jr., Phi Sigma Kappa". Part of Acc 986 that was combined with Acc 865.
  - 1939 Cherry Tree Yearbook (Box 18, Folder 2)
    This is the 1939 Cherry Tree yearbook of Grant Sherk, Jr. An inspription on the inside cover reads, "Grant R. Sherk, Jr., Phi Sigma Kappa, 1765 Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., Washington, D.C. ". Part of Acc 986 that was combined with Acc 865.
  - 1940 Cherry Tree Yearbook (Box 18, Folder 3)
    This is the 1940 Cherry Tree yearbook of Grant Sherk, Jr. An inspription on the inside cover reads, "Grant R. Sherk, Jr., Phi Sigma Kappa, 1765 Massachusetts Avenue, N.W., Washington, D.C. ". Part of Acc 986 that was combined with Acc 865.
  - 1941 Cherry Tree Yearbook (Box 18, Folder 4)
    This is the 1941 Cherry Tree yearbook of Grant Sherk, Jr. Part of Acc 986 that was combined with Acc 865.
- Newspapers, magazines, newsletters, 1933-1998; MS2130 Series 7; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 7, Box 20)
  This collection contains newspaper articles and correspondence. They range in date from 1933 to 1998.
  This material contains articles from The George Washington University Athletic Review about GW football games, and Hatchet articles and correspondence relating to Don Balfour's G.I. Bill.
  - George Washington University Athletic Review, October 21, 1933, 10/21/1933 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    This George Washington University Athletic Review dates to October 21, 1933. The cover features a signed picture of Kermit Stewart and reads: "Auburn vs. George Washington, Griffith Stadium, October 21, 1933". Handwritten comments about various team members are found throughout the program. Futhermore, this Athletic Review is autographed by many team players.
    Francis Strayer presented these materials to the University in October of 1993. Strayer was a 1934 graduate of the university, playing both football and baseball for GW. This note was written in 2005.
  - George Washington University Athletic Review, October 26, 1934, 10/26/1934 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    Three copies of the George Washington University Athletic Review that date to October 26, 1934. The cover features a picture of Henry Strayer, G.W. Guard and reads: "Wake Forest vs. George Washington, Griffith Stadium, October 26, 1934". Handwritten comments about various team members are noted throughout the program. Futhermore, the cover of this Athletic Review is signed by Henry "Hank" Strayer.
    Francis Henry Strayer presented these materials to the University in October of 1993. Strayer was a 1934 graduate of the university, playing both football and baseball for GW. This note was written in 2005.
  - George Washington University Athletic Review, November 23, 1934, 11/23/1934 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    This copy of the George Washington University Athletic Review that dates to November 23, 1934. The cover features a picture of Harry Deming, G.W. Tackle and reads: "North Dakota vs. George Washington, Griffith Stadium, November 23, 1934". Handwritten comments about various team members are noted throughout the program.
  - Football newspaper clippings, 1949 -1953 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    These clippings concern football games between the years 1949-1953. Also included are football programs and a couple of photographs from games. These news clippings were collected by Thomas Flyzik, a former GW football player. They were donated by Betty Flyzik in 1994. Formerly Acc 231.
  - Various issues of GW Hatchet, 1941-1946 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    This folder contains various GW Hatchet articles relating to Don Balfour's time at GW and participation in G.I. Bill. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
    Don Balfour interviewed the new commissioner for the GI Bill while serving as editor for the GW Hatchet. At the meeting he signed up for the GI Bill (having served in the U.S. Army before attending GW) and thus became the first recipient of the GI Bill in the United States. Mr. Balfour donated his materials from his Hatchet days and information on the first GI Bill to the University Archives. Formerly Acc 1022.
  - Correspondence regarding Balfour at GW and G.I. Bill, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    This folder contains various correspondence relating to Don Balfour's time at GW and participation in G.I. Bill. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
  - Smithsonian Magazine article on G.I. Bill and correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    This folder contains a Smithsonian Magazine article on Don Balfour's time at GW and participation in G.I. Bill. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
  - GW Magazine on World War II, Fall 1995 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    This folder contains a GW Magazine article on WW II. The article mentions Balfour on page 13. This folder also contains correspondence ranging from 1994 to 1995. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
  - Correspondence and clippings relating to PBS documentary, "The G.I. Bill, the Law that Changed America", 01/1997 --01/1998 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    This folder contains correspondence ranging from January 1997- January 1998. It concerns the PBS documentary, "The G.I. Bill, the Law that Changed America" in which Don Balfour appeared in. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
  - Correspondence from E. Keith Johnson regarding Balfour and the G.I. Bill, 2001, 07/2001 --08/2001 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    This folder contains correspondence from E. Keith Johnson regarding Balfour and G.I. Bill. These range in date from July to August 2001. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
  - Correspondence from E. Keith Johnson regarding Balfour and the G.I. Bill, 2002, 01/2002 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    This folder contains correspondence from E. Keith Johnson regarding Balfour and G.I. Bill. These date to January 2002. Don Balfour is a 1944 graduate of The George Washington University with an Associates of Arts (AA) degree from the Columbian School of Arts and Sciences. The following year (1945) he earned a Bachelors degree (BA). While attending the university, Mr. Balfour worked as a reporter and later editor of the GW "Hatchet". He was also active with the University Glee Club and Cue and Curtin (drama).
- Professional tools, ca.1962; MS2130 Series 8; 3 Linear foot (Box 17, Box 22, Box 23)
  This collection contains a medical bag and medical instruments belonging to Dr. George Nordlinger. They date to ca. 1962.
  - Medical bag, 1962 ca. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Black leather medical bag from Dr. George Nordlinger. George Nordlinger (1897-1994) was a member of The George Washington University community for over three quarters of a century, as a student, faculty member and emeritus professor. A life-long Washington, D.C. resident, he was born there April 30, 1897. He graduated from Western High School, and from GW with an A.B. degree in 1918. From the time he was a small boy he wanted to be a doctor, and went on to Medical School at GW, receiving his M.D. in 1922. Three years later, after doing work in hospitals in the U.S., Dublin and Vienna, he returned to begin what would be a thirty-seven year faculty appointment teaching obstetrics and gynecology. He was fondly known as \Uncle George\ to students who took his courses, including the first courses on birth control offered by the School in 1930.
    This item was donated to the University Archives by the Dean of the Medical School in 2000. Note also that Dr. Nordlinger's daughter Joan donated his cap and gown, diploma, and other certificates in 2003. An oral history was done with Dr. Nordlinger in 1991, and can be found in MS0371, the Oral History Collection. Formerly ACC#810.
  - Medical Instruments, 1962 ca. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    This box contains various medical instruments from Dr. George Nordlinger. They include such objects as stethascopes, scaples, syringes and various specula. George Nordlinger (1897-1994) was a member of The George Washington University community for over three quarters of a century, as a student, faculty member and emeritus professor. Formerly ACC#810.
  - Medical Instruments, 1962 ca. (Box 23, Folder 1)
    This box contains various medical instruments from Dr. George Nordlinger. They include such objects as stethascopes, scaples, and various specula. George Nordlinger (1897-1994) was a member of The George Washington University community for over three quarters of a century, as a student, faculty member and emeritus professor. Formerly ACC#810.